hi guys welcome back to the money
control live stream you are watching
markets with santo and cj
well
the weekend is just half an hour away
but there is no yay in this on this
friday for the last treat indices are
all set to close in the red deep red
well cj something similar to what i've
been saying all throughout that there's
a market which is not going anywhere in
a hurry it just takes one step forward
and then moves two steps backwards well
gloat away glued away santo
what but what is driving this market
crazy what is pulling the market you
know indices lower well for starters it
seems that inve traders are just
unwilling to carry out carry on their
open positions to monday because
the weekend is coming up and in a highly
volatile environment that we are
currently in
anything can any bad news can come out
and that can catch traders especially
those who want to take bullish positions
on the wrong foot given what is
happening with russia ukraine you could
have their stock of new sanctions on
russia anytime now so in traders just
want to be cautious and safe at this
point of time they do not want to stick
their neck out it seems and you know
that said there is there is actually a
little bit of glimmer of hope and that
hope is coming from once again yours
truly retail investors the nifty small
cap index actually was largely in the
green
just before just five minutes ago it
turned into the red but it's still
outperforming many of its mid cap and
large cap years the nifty small cap
hundred index was down above 104 0.4
percent uh which basically tells you a
lot of money has been pumped in by
retail investors although we have seen a
little bit of minor profit booking
towards the end now yes cj also it's a
little surprising you know when i've
been talking to traders and
investors overall the near-term outlook
on the market remains bullish and i
failed to see why given so many
negatives which are there on the horizon
but still
the general feeling is that mid cap and
small cap share should continue to do
well in the short term well i hope
you're right and the dealers and traders
that you are speaking to are bang on
that said well markets are where we left
them off in in the morning but there was
some spectacular action happening on
individual counters right santo well
metal stocks today uh were among the
notable underperformers particularly
aluminium shares led by hindalco
hindalco was down a little over five
percent today mainly the rub off effect
of alcoa reporting disappointing
quarterly numbers well it if you look at
it one way it was not really
disappointing numbers but as usual you
never know what the
alcoa is basically one of the biggest
aluminium producers out there and
generally
when you have a market leader global
market leader reporting earnings in a
particular industry as close as
aluminium is it will tend to have a
rub-off effect on even indian yeah but
but there's an important point if you
read the commentary you know what
they're saying is that basically because
of this supply chain disruptions and and
the increase in prices that is leading
to softer demand from the consumer so
clearly high prices and supply
descriptions put together is forcing
some kind of a push back from consumers
and they're they're kind of uh deferring
their orders so this point you were
making earlier all throughout that high
ma you know high costs are always good
for the producers doesn't really work
that way at least you're seeing that in
the case of aluminium yeah well
let's look at the facts alcoa reported
record high earnings yes
analysts were expecting it to report
even greater numbers but if you look at
it in a very standalone and absolute
sense alcohol's number record profit
record operating profit and even the
commentary from the management is is not
that bad they're expecting
the average realization in the aluminium
business to be higher than what they
reported in the first quarter or the
march quarter of this year that tells me
only one thing that profitability is
going to improve it's not going to go
down or stabilize at this current level
next up uh aluminium prices are going to
stay elevated because remember there are
sanctions being imposed on russia
which are not going to be withdrawn even
if the war were to end tomorrow right
sanctions are political instruments so
they take years to wind down i mean just
look at what is happening with
you know iran it has taken years to wind
down those sanctions and now they were
they were back again in 2015. that said
hindalco per se it's had a stellar show
over the past one year i mean almost
record profits record profitability
almost on a quarterly basis and this
quarter is this quarter and the next
quarter specifically is not going to be
any different
i mean just to give you a reference
point kotak equities expects
112 percent year-on-year growth in queue
for a bit of indulge so that tells you
and gives you a picture of the sense of
you know momentum that earnings of india
alcohol is often it's not just about the
earnings cj if you push the share price
up sharply then accordingly expectations
also goes up right yeah but that does
not change the longer term picture for
the for the stock we can continue we can
continue arguing over there absolutely
we can that's out of bff that's like
another stock driver really you know in
in among the you know market chatter was
adani ports the company uh came out with
with a new with a report of an
acquisition they have uh acquired a
marine services company called if i'm
not wrong ocean sparkles right and so
this acquisition now why is this
acquisition important
ocean spark is largely into marine
services including dredging a lot of
port services a lot of vessel services
and given that adani ports has been you
know
expanding its footprint around india
it's been acquiring distressed sports
all all over the country and all because
it expects cargo volumes to go up as
india's growth rate jumps up as the
export side of the economy goes does
well it expects a lot of increase in
cargo volumes and this acquisition is
largely going to add into the current
story of adani ports plus on on a but
ebitda level as well if you believe what
analysts are saying the the acquisition
should add to adani
well cj you place too much faith in
analysts and if i speak about valuations
again you'll say that i'm sounding like
a
stuck record anyway now see the ports
business is heavily dependent on you
know global trade yeah and the outlook
for that if you see the outlook for
global economic growth that's being you
know the focus are being steadily
downgraded so that should tell you
something about where you know the kind
of impact that would have on global
trade that's one point secondly if you
look at adani port's profit numbers over
the last you know the top line has been
growing steadily but none of that is
really flowing into the into the bottom
line the profits have been fairly range
bound over the last that is because they
have been investing a lot of their money
back that is that is the reason why it
is probably not reflecting on the you
know margin probably profitability as
well as fair point and lastly you know
how much would you pay for a sport
business so right now they're quoting at
about 26 odd times forward earnings
which again the same analysts say that
is fairly expensive for a port's
business so considering all these
factors i would say that it's a slightly
risky play at this point there are
always you know exceptions to the
historical trend a lot of the analysts
also that you you talk about tend to
depend a lot on what what has happened
in the history and sometimes there are
odd companies who tend to defy defy
history we have had many examples in the
market right
well ics lombard the stock was down
close to about six percent badly hit
today yes uh it reported quarterly
numbers yesterday and the numbers were
way short of market expectations which
is why you saw a huge sell-off in the
stock yeah i think it was a very symptom
i mean ics lombard's you know the stock
performance today was very symptomatic
of the mood of this market i mean if you
have
if you're you're underperforming just by
a little bit right market is punishing
you very heavily
you know
which what happens when prices move up
ahead of fundamentals this is bound to
happen nothing surprising yet and there
are also some lingering concerns about
icici bank you know uh planning to
reduce its stake in icsc lombard so the
picture not looking very pretty for the
stock at this point no i feel if you go
by with just today's performance maybe
the picture is not looking that pretty
but if you just zoom out a little bit
there are some factors that you know
investors who are in iso lombard can
take heart from for starters interest
rates are expected to rise as we know i
mean even at home globally we have heard
interests are already rising but even at
home a lot of economists expect rbi to
start raising rates as soon as what june
the june meeting now higher interest
rates are expected to be beneficial for
ics and lombard especially in its debt
investment portfolio because higher
interest rate will increase the yield
that it is earning on its debt portfolio
that is one second point is that you
know the after the slowdown that we have
seen in the health uh healthcare segment
of uh isa lombard the health insurance
business where it lost market share
to some of its peers during the past one
and a half years that analysts expect
the worst is over there they are going
to recover a lot of that market share
going going ahead and the management has
promised aggressive top line growth
going ahead so and healthcare would
probably healthcare insurance will
probably be one of the driving factors
for that and lastly
there is an indication that motor
insurance premiums from third party
could rise and if that happens given
that you know isa lombard's
portfolio of
general insurance is largely tilted
towards motor insurance as well it could
be it could be a standard beneficiary of
that move as well so it's not all bad
news if you just go by today's price
actually from a longer term perspective
maybe not possibly you have an
interesting stock on your counter i
really want to talk about this one okay
yes i knew you would be waiting for that
sbi cards the stock was among the few
gainers in today's wheat market up about
close to two percent there was a block
deal of close to 21 lakh shares in this
uh stock today and there's been some
improvement in the stock price over the
last few trading sessions also an
increase in trading volumes as well now
sbi card is one of the play on the
reopening of the economy more people go
out more they spend i think that's the
general assumption yes yes do you have
anything to counter that at them
absolutely so
yeah i take your point people are going
out so therefore banks and companies
like sbi cards have been able to sell a
lot more credit cards but selling credit
card does not automatically translate
into higher spending on those credit
cards right if you look at the latest
data that has come out for february
spend
spending strong credit cards have hit a
seven month low which is also telling
you a lot about where the consumer mode
is right now but does it say that hbi
cards spending on sba cards has also
come down
it does not say directly that but if an
industry level you know if you're seeing
a decline in spending that will i'm i
will assume that the market leader one
of the market leaders will be affected
first given that sgfc bank has not been
doing much anyway lately because of they
have just come out of the ban from rbi
uh
next up so now this is uh there are two
parts of this uh argument first of all
credit cards have started to take a bad
name in myself because
the past one and a half years we have
seen the rise of influencers right on
instagram twitter on youtube and a lot
of these guys have been telling a lot of
their viewers that how credit card is
bad for their financial health and that
has given credit card a bad name at
large and possibly some of this lack of
spending because it's not like consumers
have not been spending we have talked
about revenge traveling we have talked
about you know restaurant business is
doing well so it's not like consumers
are not
spending is it that maybe they are not
as happy to spend out of their credit
card as they used to be once upon a time
well if they're indisciplined then i'm
not really surprised because see if used
properly credit card is a really good
tool but i count on you to pass
judgments on other spending habits santo
and lastly uh there is competition also
emerging for credit cards and that is
emerging from the in the recent you know
uh trend of buy now pay later schemes
now a lot of merchants are getting into
it we know that buy now appeal it pay
later has become the thing in the start
of space at least
by another name in a way yeah exactly
without a card and so therefore it i
mean more than what a lot of people
think that maybe upi will eat into
credit card uh credit card business of a
lot of these companies i feel that the
greater competition or threat could come
from by an operator
that said uh so my next talk is uh is an
interesting one actually and you would
have something to say about given the
history of the promoter here so sterling
technologies um the stock rallied about
more than 13 at one point of time today
and of course the natural question you
know appears that if it is a rally 13
then is there any worth in buying the
stock now
now
why the stock rallied reports came out
earlier today that the promoters are
looking to induct strategic investors
into the three major verticals of
starlight uh technologies the three
verticals are which ones their optical
fiber
network services the telecom network
services and the software services of uh
solid tech now within the group which is
the promoter group uh they
hindu report basically quoted vedanta's
chairman anil agarwal talking about
selling about 25 stake and each of the
verticals that too at a valuation of two
billion dollar each right so that makes
a cumulative uh valuation of sterlite
tech at what six billion dollars right
current market cap even if you account
for today's gains the current market cap
of sterling tech is around 1.2 to 1.5
billion dollars that means prices
you know current marketplace have to
rise almost 5x to meet the promoters
valuation for that well cj you're the
one who always believes in the judgment
of the market so you know if the current
market cap is low right then there is a
reason why the market is assigning that
and if you can
you have that reason yeah again just
look at the numbers uh both top line as
well as bottom line for the last
about eight quarters and they've really
not gone anywhere so in in that sense
you know there is a reason why the
market is uh uh you know has assigned a
lower multiple for the stock but and
this is more of a case of momentum by i
mean i'm not saying it can't go up
probably it could well go up i mean
there'll be many like you who believe
that you know probably this is a great
stock because the promoter states that
it's undervalued but other than if i
were to purely look at fundamentals then
i think i would give the stock a pass
well if smart money is willing to pay
that much then who am i to judge why why
would i counter there so retail is the
new smart money it is it is of course it
is okay that said uh you know we should
take a status check on on the market and
i'll just uh check my money control app
and see where the market is right now
selling has intensified yes over the
last half an hour
50 50 is one down one point three nifty
bank is down two percent santo and mid
caps which are holding firm till uh
about half an hour back they've also
slipped into the red yes even nifty
small cap index is down about 0.4
percent zero point five percent so yeah
it's a very red
red closing for the market on a friday
there is no weekend chair
on the last street today man it doesn't
look like it's here that said uh
is there something we have missed yes uh
see are you used to you know badly uh
addicted to air conditioners absolutely
in bombay heat in bombay heat you can't
live without yeah well then i've got
some bad news for you so almost uh
fourth of india's power generation
uh capacity has been shut okay now the
big reason for that is
coal shortage as we all know coal prices
have been going up uh besides there are
supply chain problems also
so also what are you telling me man i
feel that there is some bad news coming
here so yeah the bad news is that
obviously you'll have to brace for power
cuts as simple as that because
yeah because if there's not enough
generation that's too obvious fallout
right and i hope that they don't happen
over the weekend at least yeah the other
reason is that many discounts have not
been paying power generation companies
on time because of which power
generation companies say that they are
unable to buy again it wasn't this like
is this for 2015 yeah this is this is a
recurring story of the power sector for
all that excitement over power stocks
but
you know santo as they say in the market
and you would know this your generation
has been the one which has brought this
up this you know saying that every
crisis is always an opportunity right
there is always an opportunity that you
can find in a crisis
and i think for from an investor's point
of view this crisis could actually end
up being an opportunity has already been
playing out we've known that power
stocks have been doing quite well over
the past past two or three weeks of
course a part of is that you know it's
power stocks are usually considered as
the best bet to be if interest rates are
rising if there's volatility in the
market given that their earnings are
generally stable right but
in a scenario where coal shortages are
reducing power you know power production
and
it is very likely given that you know
the news reports that are coming in
already maharashtra gujarat and tamil
nadu reportedly have started importing
coal from other places
give it even though a few years ago
there was this policy that we want to
reduce our you know coal imports
high coal imports will be done at a
higher prices because they have been
done at international prices right now
this higher price will of course
naturally increase the cost of power
production but
the indication that analysts have right
now is that
a lot of the regulators will be you know
uh
sanguine about raising tariffs for power
companies they would be they would not
let power companies bear the cost this
is also all shortages political issue
you seem to forget that
on paper this argument looks very sound
but you know when people protest then it
will be a different picture altogether
but
yeah i mean yeah that too in an
inflationary environment i i can see
that happening but as of now there are
no indication of that but the indication
that analysts are getting is that we
could see power power tariff hikes going
ahead to compensate a lot of these power
producers especially in places like
mundra which have one two almost two big
power plants power generation plants uh
they could see terrifying that said nest
of spot uh power trading basically is
going to go up when you don't have you
know you're not basically getting power
from your long-term purchasing uh you
know agreements then you go to the spot
market to get whatever power you can so
that you can meet incremental demand so
that should also be beneficial for uh
you know the indian energy exchange iex
and we could see some benefit on that
side lastly the biggest benefits benefit
beneficiary out of this entire chaos is
coal india coal india has indicated that
it is going to ramp up production as
much as it can but at this point of time
it seems it's not even in coal india's
ability to meet the sort of demand that
we are seeing 38 year high power demand
in this summer that is what i was saying
yesterday and you were making all those
noises about esd and and all that kind
of stuff anyway so anyway so coal india
basically now how will coal india
benefit so coal india of course also you
know provides
uh coal in two rates it already has one
rate through which it provides to
certain power plants certain industries
manufacturing units and then there it it
has a sort of a spot market which is
also known as the e-auction market where
it generally sells coal at the whatever
the market price the market uh the price
that the market is willing to pay to it
and those prices have been rising for
the past two quarters and it is possible
that this will continue to rise because
higher international price uh higher
international prices will generally
translate into higher e-auction premiums
for coal india so these are the three
ways in disc in ways in which this
crisis can actually become an
opportunity well fair point uh so what
do you have on the horizon ct well
earnings uh we are going to get into the
thick of it i mean next week we are
going to have 10 nifty 50 companies
which have a combined market
capitalization of as much as 300 billion
dollars coming out with their q phone
numbers so it's going to be all stock
selective action
i am pretty sure that even the macro
backdrop is going to you know fade away
a little bit given that so much of
numbers are going to come out not really
cj because i think when
it will largely depend on the macro
backdrop because if the sentiment is
gloomy then the slightest miss means
that all these stocks will get punished
very heavily and i hope that if the
sentiment is gloomy then even the
slightest of uh outperformance also
rewards very hard no the slightest of
outperformance means you'll not get
beaten that's supported you'll be
allowed to hold it if you look at
science performance today it tells me a
different story that said
i say a bank is going to come out with
its number tomorrow hul bajaj auto we
have access bank wipro maruti suzuki
coming out with all all of these big big
heavyweights are going to come out with
their q4 numbers so earnings will
definitely be the driving force next
week well with that it's time to let you
get back to your trading terminals i
hope you enjoyed watching the show
that's all that we have in this episode
of markets with santo and cj
what are your weekend plans by the way
before we let them go
well uh maybe i'll catch up on a few
movies movies yeah what about you cj
well i'm going to sleep and then i'm
going to sleep some more that's all
anyway please post your feedback on the
comment section below and do follow us
on on social media on instagram twitter
we are everywhere guys so do follow us
and we will see you on monday morning 9
a.m sharp on youtube money controls
youtube channel see you and have a great
weekend
you